And Assalamu Alaikum, so let's
discuss this topic. We will look at symmetric lines
and techniques. There are two types of
techniques, substitution techniques and
transposition techniques. Clearly, substitution techniques involve
techniques and
transposition techniques. What are these? Let's
understand this by noting on a whiteboard that
we have airplane text, which says "
Hello." This message you sent is "
Hello." You
can perform encryption on it and convert it to text on the side.
We will see in two ways. What are those two ways? Let's
convert "Hello" to "Hello." Replace the "H"
character behind the "A" and
replace one character with the "
Email" character with the "Team," then the
next one is replaced with the "Betty" character and the "User." So,
when you replace plain text
characters with different characters, in
which I replaced "Hello" with "
PST." Then we have this technique
called  Is this a substitution technique, what do you
call this kind of technique, mom, this
technique with all these things, this
substitution
astatement,
then what is one character is replaced
with another different character and discard is a substitution
technique, so let's
see the other method of converting hello into reference tax,
what can be another method,
and the other method is that I change their position, that is,
I first write from the net itself, then I
bring the value, then om and
then match,
and then the l that is left for us at the end, so
you have shifted those characters forward and
backward, which is with the characters of your plain text, that is,
when you move those characters forward and
backward, that is, you will scramble, so this
kind of technique is called
transposition technique, have you
written these characters backward and forward, so what will you call that technique,
not transposition technique, our
first focus is our substitution
technique, we have to look at it, focus on the vision definition,
a substitution technique is one in which the
letter of plain text is replaced by other letters
A player, so the first technique that we will discuss in this is
what are the techniques on the Caesar side, it is the C-safar which is the
simplest subjection technique which was introduced by a
scientist Julius Caesar,
now we have two ways to solve the Caesar-Safari problem,
for this I will take a new page, the
technique that we are discussing is
what is
on the severe side,
which Safar technique can be solved in two ways, there are two methods
in the Dam book,
you will find only one method in the notes,
so here I will tell you its two methods,
what are its two methods,
we have two methods,
I will tell you this, number one is
by using formula E,
Aplayer,
hey brothers, Singh formula and its
second method is the direct method, that is,
direct method, Caesar-
Safari algorithm can be used in these two ways, so
we will discuss the first method by using
formula E, so
now  If we talk about using formula,
then we see which formulas are there in it,
we take those formulas from
here from the notes,
we have two formulas, we
go to our note support and copy them,
this formula whose metro track font
size I increase to
see
that you will use these formulas,
AC means cyber attacks,
this system of text I write here,
yes, so let us write here,
for whom is this devotion, where
which request is
in successful text, the
back call to is
plain text
and k is equal to k and
you have to remember that the value of k should be
this, you have to
remember these two formulas, the
formula of tax on the side
is the formula to convert it into gate plus k mode
on 6 skin question is called
and in description again which will be
converted into plain text, so c - k mode 06,
so here I was telling you a very important thing that
you must have  B
is that must be a
greater than or equal to one in less than or
equal to 226 players so by using formula
one we are talking about the first method so there are two
formulas to convert into side effects
so this is the formula you have
that is called school question and again to
convert into plain text so this is the
formula we have C - K most wanted
assistant professor tags patent for
plain text and K stands for key and the key
value which is from one to 26 both are
inclusive clear now let us take one more page
so first of all by using formula
you have to do your for me remember it well I have it
available here we will check it from here so first of all what
you have to do is
take ABC from here I will write you a
plain text
that we have a plain text PT
hello hello
and we have to tell its side effect on the site text
that this is we have to tell cyber attacks by
using Caesar side to tell its side effect
brothers Singh daily airplane text
hello has to be converted into side
text and  Which technique do you have to apply for
Caesar Safar, so what do you have to do for that,
simple time is third, what do you do, you should
write ABC, yes, of course, today I will
tell you ABC, you will write it completely, so
see, I have written it from A to Z, but
you can see that from here
what do you have to do ABC, but this is the
first step of the solution,
now what do you have to do next, you have to
sign the numbers, you will
sign each alphabet one
similarly by code to increasing order,
free 4,
five, key and
shone, so
you can see that
when you sign the number to each alphabet, it becomes something like this that a
value is
assigned to one, honorific value to
three and so on, the value of Z is
assigned to six because
what value we have is greater than or
equal to one and generic 128 206 player,
now we see that we have to
apply the formula of
a formula here, what do you have formula
See what is the safar tax, plus the mode is
226,
so here on your
side you will convert the tax into the vector
color of attacks, first you will
find the side effect, first you
should see what is the plane tech tractor, its side effect is found, so write
fiber text of match, a
request to people was kept,
what is the value of that, that is, a plane tech from four, right,
what is the planets, so
see the value of its cross quarter inch here, you are
getting this, its value is HP gas value is
8:00,
so take it in place of ash, sorry people, we will
test it, 8 plus and in this it is also
mentioned that I forgot to tell you, there is
one from the left, the
value of which is f4, so we will cook it in the formula here
and
write g hall, the mode
of the number is 26th,
then we will solve it, it is
equal to 12th mode 26th, so
what is the answer to the first mode,
its answer is also twelve, I am making you
write only one note, write one
See,
I will tell you this in one night,
if you have it written
and that we do
not do it here, rather I will
show you the essence of it in your mind, how to do it,
if you write for
airplane mode how to, then
how to solve it, you subtract
24, mode from two, it
brings you the reminder operator, right,
what is the answer, zero,
then the answer to for motu, what do you write,
zero, which is left,
if I say for the first number, this
is and for the second number, I say
ab, then
you can also find this mode like this,
if only one value is increased,
if you are writing,
I am just writing k
greater ba bb, then this is the
way to find the mode, do you also add that number,
which is the rest, this is its effect,
but if you also have this Lansdown,
like I write two
airplane mode the
four, then see here, there is only one value two,
that is left, so in this way, you will
not add the zero, rather that two will be your answer.  This is
your simple
answer which will come, just press the balance
mode, the answer will be a
party of a greater than 10th, divide
and remainder will be the answer, so
see here, 12th is smaller than 26,
so its answer will be 12, now what you have to do is
find out
which character is the 12th gas, from here find out,
you have ₹2 against, the
character you are seeing is 1, so the
journey tax that will be formed will be
clear, similarly you find out the
second character, what is coming after the match, it is
absolutely fine, friend, so let's find out a good
effect, how will we do it, the
same formula is
that you write the
text on the side of C, now which
character is one, who is
equal to formula, the plain text of happy plus,
gas number is 5,
so what will come here,
what is the value of one pipe loss, f4 is
and mod
plain mod so 16 is
its  If you are doing it for this then
what will come here,
yes sir absolutely the answer to this is G9
airplane mod
206 so what will you write as its answer, we will write nine only,
so guests from Noida see which character you are getting, that is i, then
what will you write in place of note, we will write i, that is
care, similarly for mail also I will
tell you how to do it for mail,
yes sir apply the same formula for Abel, on the
side
in the text of help there is a
formula G plus
MP3 dhele see the corresponding number,
you are getting total 12:00
A plus k plus 4
airplane mod
quantity sex,
so what answer do you get,
airplane mod 226,
from where did you get this, it is
sixteen,
so 16th equal character see which
one you are getting, you are
getting A P, so from
here let me tell you that you have the
text against the match which you got on the side,
that is
e-mail, the
character which you got after A P, that is i, that of the
game  The character you got next is that
you got
gas behind it, if you got p then
put next and put gas vipin, if you solve for ok then
you will get the character for
yes
a lamp, so your plain text and hello,
this is your plant extra, I am writing this as
ppt on,
your plain text
hello hello has been converted,
what about in travel tax, match's hostel got di,
yagya staff got i on
this double k sp neelabh, secondly alka
gas miyan will get piece and ok gas will get
you s, so your
hello text has been converted, li
double p s, this has become yours,
using formula after ct we can apply it like this,
now what you have to do is to
convert the text on this side again
in plain tax, you know
which formula you will use,
this is the formula e,
its solution is present in cafe notes,
you can see how it has been
enlightened, if you got oil, against k
you got i, the character you got in front of the game is
p, similarly you will
get different recipes  Okay, so you got it like this, so
your text which has been converted from hello has been
converted to lip player, let me
tell you in the direct method that
now your message has been sent, now we are talking about the
direct method, let me take a
new
direct method, the
direct method with
formula is also very easy, what do
you have to do in track math, you simply
focus on your ABC here, if you
focus on your ABC, what is the size of it, it is
important, it is four,
here your first character is
h, so you start counting from the match
and count till four,
see the expectorant, start counting
that i, second character j, third and k, and so
you have to jump to four, chyavan i20 30 k,
fourth, so the next character you got is the
email test, will be replaced by email on the
middle, which is
replaced and replaced by
aplayer,
similarly now look at the next character, the
next character is yours,
move the pointer on and play the jam of four,
move the point on play
that jam of one  Two's birth, 3 and 4, so
Ganesha, what did you get, did you get it, what did
GameStop get,
yes brother, I got it,
next, if you have an
email, then you go to point airplane
in help, point brought four's birth play one two
234,
so you are getting like P at night,
guest of email, what are you getting, you are getting
AP
and what will you get on net style gas and
they will get real
AP only
and see the last character, what is it,
I have that,
first I have placed the pointer, I have got the first
four's birth play 12345,
so what gas have I got in this, so let me
tell you the track method again, you have to
look at your first character, H,
take the point on it and
take a jump of that much, the birth of four present on H,
play 1234, so the app has got the next character jewel, it is
important that the competition will get
three's birth or two, then you will get two's
birth click similarly when you have to go to your travel
text, now again
in play interact, you have to reverse it as it
was in help
I should get a match through email, play
your album and bring point value four,
you have to go to the bank 1234, then you will get it, you will get
light gas, the truth is this is a
direct formula, you can also see it in the notes, on the
internet, by taking Caesar Safar, you will get
its details clearly, you can take
advantage of this example, you
can add this contest and if there is any
problem then you can ask me, okay,
thank you ji, Saala office